GIANLUCA BOO

uк 2 Kingsbury Cottages, 26B Kingsbury's Lane, Ringwood, BH24 1EL, United Kingdom +44 7423 393884

ch Via Stazione 16, 6743 Bodio, Switzerland +41 76 449 34 93

EMAIL gianluca@idiosyncraticmapper.net www.idiosyncraticmapper.net

NATIONALITY Swiss, Italian



ABOUT

I apply my research skills in the fields of **spatial analysis** and **statistical modeling** to tackle relevant societal issues. During my career, I focused on the mapping and estimation of geographic phenomena in the domains of **epidemiology**, **demography**, and **urban planning**. As part of the GRID3 project, I recently produced model-based population estimates for five provinces of the **Democratic Republic of Congo** to support **public health intervention**.

EMPLOYMENT

Research Fellow | spatial demography [April 2018 – Present] World Pop, University of Southampton, United Kingdom

Research and Teaching Assistant | spatial epidemiology [January 2014 - March 2018] Department of Geography, University of Zurich, Switzerland

Geoinformatician | urban planning [February 2011 - December 2013] Planning and Construction Office of Canton Fribourg, Switzerland

GIS Manager | urban planning [January 2010 - August 2010] International Peace and Cooperation Centre Jerusalem, Israel/Palestine

Human Rights Observer | humanitarian [July 2009 - November 2009]

Peace Watch Switzerland, Jerusalem, Israel/Palestine

Substitute Teacher | mathematics and geography [May 2007 - June 2009] Several secondary schools in Canton Ticino, Switzerland

Urban Planning Intern | urban planning [December 2006 - April 2007]

Department of Territory of Canton Ticino, Switzerland

EDUCATION

PhD in Geography | GIScience [July 2018]

Department of Geography, University of Zurich, Switzerland

 $\textbf{Postgraduate Certificate} \mid GIScience \; [\texttt{February} \; \texttt{2013}]$

SPINLab, VU University Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Master of Science in Geography | urban studies [June 2009]

Department of Geography, University of Lausanne, Switzerland

Bachelor of Science in Geography | human geography [June 2006]

Department of Geography, University of Lausanne, Switzerland

CURRICULUM VITAE 1 | 2

TRAINING

Open GeoHub summer school – spatial and spatiotemporal computing [September 2019]

Department of Geoinformatics, University of Münster, Germany

Spatial and spatio-temporal Bayesian models with R-INLA [September 2019]

School of Public Health, Imperial College London, United Kingdom

Modeling spatial and spatio-temporal areal unit data in R with CARBayes [September 2017]

Instituto de Investigação e Inovação em Saúde, Universidade do Porto, Portugal

Machine learning methods for spatial and temporal analysis [September 2016]

SpaceTime Lab for Big Data Analytics, University College London, United Kingdom

Bayesian modelling and computation [September 2016]

Department of Statistics, University of Southampton, United Kingdom

Project management for research [March 2015]

Graduate School in Geography, University of Zurich, Switzerland

SKILLS

PERSONAL Innovative, independent, interdisciplinary, and organized

METHODS Scientific research [academic writing, oral and poster presentations, and academic teaching], spatial analysis

[mapping, cluster analysis, spatial interpolation, and spatial regression], statistical analysis [descriptive statistics, statistical modeling – frequentist and Bayesian, and power tests], and machine learning [clustering, cross-

validation, and decision trees]

SOFTWARE Geographic information systems [ArcGIS, QGIS], (spatial-)data analysis [RStudio – Markdown, and

Shiny], graphic design [Adobe Design Suite], and general [Microsoft Office, and Google Suite]

 $\qquad \qquad R \ [\text{interactive visualizations, data management, spatial, analysis, and statistical modeling}], \ Python \ [\text{geographic}]$

information systems], HTML and CSS [web design], and JavaScript[web mapping]

LANGUAGE Italian [mother tongue], English [full working proficiency], French [full working proficiency], German [limited

working proficiency], and Spanish [beginner]

SELCTED PUBLICATIONS

Thomson DR, Kuffer M, **Boo G**, Hati B, Grippa T, Elsey H, Linard C, Mahabir R, Kyobutungi C, Mwaniki D, Ndugwa, Makau J et al. *Proposing an integrated approach to neighbourhood deprivation mapping in LMICs*. Wellcome Open Research [UNDER REVIEW]

Paternoster G, **Boo G**, Wang C, Minbaeva G, Usubalieva J, Raimkulov KM, Zhoroev A, Abdykerimov KK, Kronenberg PA, Müllhaupt B, Furrer R, Deplazes P, and Torgerson PR. *Epidemic echinococcosis in Kyrgyzstan – high-resolution maps using national surveillance data identify disease hotspots*. The Lancet Global Health [UNDER REVIEW]

Boo G, Leyk S, Fabrikant SI, Graf R, and Pospishil A. 2019. Assessing uncertainty in canine cancer data sources through dasymetric refinement. Frontiers in Veterinary Science. 6:45

Boo G, Leyk S, Brunsdon C, Graf R, Pospishil A, and Fabrikant SI. 2018. *The importance of regional models in assessing canine cancer incidences in Switzerland*. PLOS One. 13(4)

Boo G, Leyk S, Fabrikant SI, Pospishil A, and Graf R. 2017. Assessing effects of structural zeros on models of canine cancer incidence: a case study of the Swiss Canine Cancer Registry. Geospatial Health. 12(1):121-129

REFERENCES

Upon request.

CURRICULUM VITAE 2 | 2